A Guide to the Barrow Family Papers, 1828-1918
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Barrow Family Papers, 1828-1918
The Library of Virginia
43261
.23 cubic feet (1 box)
Barrow family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of J. Larry Williamson, Crewe, Virginia, 24 May 2007.
Biographical Information
Edward Barrow (b. 1828) and Louisa J. Peace (b. 1839) married in 1858. Together they had at least seven children, named Mary E. W. (b. 1859), Edward Lee (b. 1861), Cora L. (b. 1868), Wilbur (b. 1871), Fannie May (b. 1874), Walter L. (b. 1876), and Lucy A. (b. 1881). Fannie May was often referred to simply as "May," and Lucy A. may be the "Lucy Archer" addressed in several of the letters in this collection. The Barrow family was fairly prominent in Brunswick County, owning substantial property and a country store called Barrow's Store.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1828-1918, of the Barrow family of Brunswick County, Virginia, chiefly consisting of letters written to Fannie May Barrow (b. 1874) discussing social calls, church services and gatherings, and other personal news and updates on common acquaintances. Correspondents include Indie Saunders (b. ca. 1875), Lizzie Doyle (b. 1874), Florence Rux (b. 1872), Hattie Lee Laffoon (b. 1881), Della E. Laffoon (b. 1879), Mary A. Marcuson (b. 1886), Dora L. Cheely (b. 1884), Lizzie T. Jones (b. 1884), and Fannie May's brother Edward L. Barrow (b. 1861). Also includes a Barrow family Bible record, 1828-1871; a handful of receipts, 1833-1918; a small notebook, 1848-1875, initially kept by Edward Barrow (b. 1828) and containing some accounts; and miscellaneous items including two small, unidentified photographic portraits, a July 1896 issue of The World for Christ, and an agreement, 1902, regarding interest in the sale of timber from a tract of land in Louisa J. Barrow's (b. 1839) family.
Contents List
- Barrow family papers, 1848-1918., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Barrow family Bible record, 1828-1871 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edward Barrow notebook, 1848-1875 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Dora L. Cheely to May Barrow, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Edward L. Barrow to May Barrow, 1892-1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Florence Rux to May Barrow, 1889-1890 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Hattie Lee Laffoon and Della Laffoon to May Barrow, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Hattye B[--?] to May Barrow, 1895-1896, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Indie Saunders to May Barrow, 1889-1894 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Lizzie Doyle to May Barrow, 1894, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters, Lizzie T. Jones to May Barrow, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters, Mary A. Marcuson to May Barrow, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters, miscellaneous, 1864-1909 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters, various authors to Lucy Archer, 1901-1908 [?] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters, various authors to May Barrow, 1893-1909 and n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Receipts, 1833-1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)